soon forgot their existence.
The mystery of where the milk went to was soon cleared up.
It was mixed every day into the pigs' mash.
The early apples were now ripening and the grass of the orchard was littered with windfalls.
The animals had assumed, as a matter of course, that these would be shared out equally.
One day, however, the order went forth that all the windfalls were to be
collected and brought to the harness room for the use of the pigs.
At this, some of the other animals murmured, but it was no use.
All the pigs were in full agreement on this point, even Snowball and Napoleon.
Squealer was sent to make the necessary explanations to the others.
>> Comrades, you do not imagine, I hope, that we pigs are doing this in a spirit
of selfishness and privilege. Many of us actually dislike milk and apples. I
dislike them myself. Our sole object in taking these things is to preserve our
health. Milk and apples, this has been proved by science, comrades, contains
substances absolutely necessary to the well-being of a pig. We pigs are brain
workers. The whole management and organization of this farm depend on us.
Day and night, we are watching over your welfare. It is for your sake that we
drink that milk and eat those apples. Do you know what would happen if we pigs
failed in our duty?
Jones would come back. Yes, Jones would come back. Surely, comrades,
>> cried Squealer almost pleadingly, skipping from side to side and whisking his tail.
>> Surely, there is no one among you who wants to see Jones come back.
>> Now, if there was one thing that the animals were completely certain of, it
was that they did not want Jones back.
When it was put to them in this light, they had no more to say.
The importance of keeping the pigs in good health was all too obvious.
So, it was agreed, without further argument, that the milk and the windfall
apples, and also the main crop of apples